holidaycottages.co.uk 2017-07-14

# Privacy Policy - holidaycottages.co.uk

Your privacy is of the utmost importance, we are therefore committed to safeguarding your personal information. We are also legally obliged to use your information in line with current legislation covering the protection of personal information, including the Data Protection Act 1998.

Who are we?

This site is owned and operated by The Travel Chapter Limited (company no 02431506), our head office is located at 5 The Quay, Bideford, Devon, EX39 2XX.

What information we collect? 

We collect personal identifiable information such as names, addresses, property details, email addresses and telephone numbers.

How we collect information?

We collect information in three ways: 

  1. Information you give us 

You may provide us with information by completing forms on our website or by contacting us via email, telephone or other means. We also collect information when you voluntarily complete customer surveys, provide feedback or participate in competitions.

  2. Information we derive from other sources 

We may also collect information about you from other sources such as public records or bodies, or through targeted research. Any personal information obtained is processed in accordance with the principles and conditions contained within the Data Protection Act 1998. 

  3. Information we collect from you 

Like most websites, when you visit our website(s) we also collect information about usage via cookies, and we also track user and traffic patterns; however, we do not collect personal information via cookies. More information on our use of cookies is detailed below in Subscriptions, Tracking and Cookies.

How we use information? 

We use information about you to process your holiday booking/reservation, manage your account or undertake holiday home letting agency activities on your behalf. 

We may also use your information to market products and services which we believe would be of interest to you, and for sending out our newsletter. You have the right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes, if you wish to opt out, please write to us at The Travel Chapter Limited, Travel Chapter House, Gammaton Road, Bideford, EX39 4DF. 

We collect information to gain a better insight into the holiday home rental market, helping us tailor our products and services accordingly, including helping to keep our website and newsletter content relevant. 

Finally we use cookies to better tailor your user experience and personalise your repeat visits to our website. 

How we safeguard information? 

We adopt best practices and operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection to safeguard personal identifiable information. 

Who we share information with? 

Any information we collect about individuals is used by The Travel Chapter Limited and its associated companies. We do not share information about individuals with any other third parties, unless we are required or allowed to do so by law. 

How you can access or correct your information? 

You have the right to request a copy of the information we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of the information we hold, please write to us at The Travel Chapter Limited, Travel Chapter House, Gammaton Road, Bideford, EX39 4DF. There may be a nominal administration charge of £10 to process your request. 

We want to ensure we have up to date and accurate personal information about you. You can ask us to correct or remove any information you think is wrong.

Other Websites

This privacy policy only applies to this website. If you follow links to other websites you should read their privacy policies. 

Children

Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. 

Changes to our privacy policy

We monitor and review our privacy policy regularly and will publish any updates on this webpage. The privacy policy was last updated on 14th June 2017 

Subscriptions, Tracking and Cookies

We offer the following free services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users: 

**Electronic newsletters**

The Travel Chapter offers a free electronic newsletter to users. The Travel Chapter gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the “Click here to unsubscribe link” provided in every newsletter. 

**"Send to a friend"**

Site users can choose to electronically forward a link to a property page to someone else by clicking "Send to a friend". The site user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know who sent the email. The information is not used for any other purpose. 

**"Live Chat"**

When the online customer service chat first begins, users are asked to enter their names in whatever format or detail they prefer. During the chat, users enter into a live question and answer session with an operator from The Travel Chapter. The Travel Chapter maintain dialogue transcripts of these chats. After the chat, we ask users to fill out an exit survey in order to obtain valuable feedback about our service. Filling out the exit survey is completely voluntary. 

Usage tracking

The Travel Chapter tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of its sites. However, The Travel Chapter does not correlate this information with data about individual users. The Travel Chapter does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser). 

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. 

Cookies

To comply with EU legislation that was introduced in May 2012, this section documents how this website might collect information as you browse and use it to provide a tailored service to improve your online experience. 

The Travel Chapter may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable The Travel Chapter to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. The Travel Chapter uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above). 

You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. You can set your browser not to accept cookies, but if you do, you may not be able to take advantage of the personalised features enjoyed by other visitors to our site such as adding properties to your favourite list and LiveChat. 

Cookies for site functionality

**Live Chat**

We use a facility called LiveChat in order to provide site users with a means of contacting a member of staff for help using the site. LiveChat sets cookies to allow us to improve the behaviour of features such as chat invitations. 

For the LiveChat Privacy Policy, including information on cookies used by LiveChat, please visit <http://www.liveperson.com/policies/customer-website-privacy>

Cookies for Site tracking 

**Inspectlet**

This is a behavioral observation tool to allow us to effectively configure our websites to perform most effectively, by monitoring the user journey. 

Inspectlet censors all data marked as sensitive, therefore data entered by the user is not transmitted or recorded to our servers.

For further information on the cookies used by Inspectlet, please visit <https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy>

**Google Analytics**

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. 

For information on the cookies used by Google Analytics, please visit <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>

**Bing Ads**

The Travel Chapter uses Bing Ads to promote our business online. To more effectively market our services, we use a cookie to record the completion of your transaction. Any information that is gathered will remain anonymous and cannot be used to identify you. 

For the Microsoft Bing Ads Privacy Policy, please visit <http://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-uk/privacy-policy>

Cookies for relevant advertising

**Google AdSense**

We use cookies from Google AdSense, to present you with adverts that may be based on the content you visit the most on our websites. The cookies show us where you saw the advert; help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns; and limit the number of times you see an advert.

To control these Google Ads, please visit [https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/”>](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb)

**Your consent**

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information by The Travel Chapter and its associated companies. If The Travel Chapter decide to change its privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information is collected, how it is used, and under what circumstances it may be disclosed.
